# JAYSON MONTERROSO SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# **ABOUT**

Software Developer for wide variety of global clients, websites and applications, With vast array of knowledge in many different front end and back end languages, responsive frameworks, databases, mobile development and best code practices., More than 10 years of experience in Web Development.Compromised to learn and improve every day my hard/soft skills.

## **OVERVIEW EXPERIENCE**

#### **GORILLA LOGIC**

Full Stack Developer | August 2017 - present

- Redesigned/Migrated marketing website for a SASS DevOps company.
- Developed global UI including assets/styles/scripts.
- Migrated all posts and content from Wordpress to Jekyll(Ruby).
- Implemented a third party CMS Service using Node+Contentful+Jekyll
- Implemented the continuos integration infrastructure using Netlify

**Stack of technologies:** HTML5 / Jekyll/ CSS3/SCSS/ Bootstrap 4, ES6/ React Node/Webpack

## **ELEVEN SYSTEMS (FORMER JETSON SYSTEMS)**

Software Developer | April 2016 - August 2017

- Creation of scalable Angular Modules for a large web application
- Hooked up restful services with complex data using Angular 2
- Implemented complex financial charts using Highcharts IS.
- Created Financial Module Page UI/UX, to support data coming from Salesforce.

Stack of technologies: Angular, HTML/5 / CSS3 / SCSS(BEM) / ES6

#### **PRODIGIOUS LATAM**

Principal Layer Engineer | April 2013 - August 2016

- Redesigned/Migrated website for smartusa.com
- Responsibilities included UI planning/development/testing and bug fixing.
- Created multiple facebook social applications and games.
- Created 3D interior viewer for vehicles in website using three.js
- Implementation of changes per client request based on compositions provided

**Stack of technologies:** AngularJS/Three.js/CSS3/SCSS(BEM)/Neat/Javascript/CoffeeScript/HTML5

## **CONTACT DETAILS**

Alajuela, Costa Rica +(506) 8706-6404 jayson.monterroso@gmail.com https://jayson.website

## ACADEMIC BACKGROUND

## UNIVERSIDAD ADVENTISTA DE CENTRO AMERICA

Bachelor of Computer Systems Engineering

# **EXPERTISE**

/Web Development Coding & Programming

Search Engine Optimization

Cross-Browser Compatibility

Site Troubleshooting

UX & UI Design

Agile Methodologies

Hosting & Maintenance

DevOps

Information Architecture

## **TECNICAL SKILLS**

#### **Back-End Development**

Node, PHP, AWS Serverless

## Front End Development:

HTML5, CSS/SASS/Compass/Neat, Javascript (ES 5/6) Bootstrap, Foundation,

Front-End Javascript Frameworks: Angular 5 &

AngularJS (1.6), React, Highcharts.js, Backbone.js,

Sencha Touch, jQuery, Three.js

Javascript Tools: Webpack, Gulp, Babel CLI,

Angular CLI, Grunt, Node CLI Tools

Native Mobile Javascript Frameworks: React

Native, Nativescript

**Databases** MongoDB, MySQL, MS SQL Server, DynamoDB S3,

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **ACCENTURE**

Web Developer | 2011 - 2013

- Worked as web developer for several projects with different global clients, websites/apps based on client requirements.
- Created hybrid mobile application (iOs/Android) using Sencha Touch 1.5 and 2.0 javascript framework | Merck Pharmaceutical.
- Worked as backend developer(php) creating the content and website architecture and functionality for a wordpress website. *costaricavacations.com*.
- Created a Wordpress Plugins to support external Razuna server upload of assest for assets management.
- Worked in the creation of a SPA to display college sports scores/statistics using Backbone.js and consuming restful services | Gatorade.

Stack of technologies: AngularJS, HTML/5/CSS3/SCSS/Compass/ Sencha Touch/Backbone.js/ jQuery/Javascript

#### **BOSZ DIGITAL**

Web Developer | 2011 | Bank of America

- Created mobile and web landing pages to support local/global marketing campaigns, based on client requirements and specifications.
- Implemented best practices for accessibility across all landing pages.
- · Certified with ADA certification for accessibility coding best practices

Stack of technologies: HTML/5/CSS3/ jQuery / jQuery Mobile/ Javascript

#### **LATITUDE TEN NORTH**

Full Stack Developer | 2010 - 2011

Responsible for evaluating the technological environment and scope of the projects and suggest possible development stacks along with timelines.

Web Developer (using PHP and CMS based on PHP Wordpress/Expression Engine) creating functional backend/frontend websites based on detailed requirements from clients.

Worked for several religious and political projects organisations in the United States (Ohio GOP/Good Samaritan)

Stack of technologies: HTML/5/CSS3/ jQuery / jQuery/Javascript/ PHP/ MySQL

# **ELECTRODOMESTICOS CASABLANCA**

Full Stack Developer | 2007 - 2010

- Full Stack Developer responsible for creation of corporate Intranet, and global website.
- In charge of design, back end, front end and content management.
- In charge of migrate MS SQL Server database to MySQL inventory tables in order to be consistent with products on internal and external website.
- Intranet was developed using a financial web service in order to determine if a client was able to receive a credit, by using his personal id.
- Stack of technologies: HTML/5/CSS3/ jQuery / jQuery/Javascript/ PHP/ MySQL/Joomla/C#/MS SQL Server

# **PROJECTS**

#### YOURSECRETCODE.COM

S3 Migration/Node Refactoring | 2017

Migration of current self-served Node instance to a Serverless Architecture using Serverless Application Framework.

Migration of Mongo Database to AWS DynamoDB.

Refactoring codebase based in node in order to improve performance and code readability.

Implementation of ES6 in the website core functions which is the book creation/generation based on user input.

Stack of technologies: Serverless Application Framework, Node JS, DynamoDB S3, Lambda Functions (node) AWS, MongoDB.

#### **TALENTO HUMANO**

Mobile Application / Backoffice Web Application /Api Services/DevOps | 2017 (5 months)

Responsible for creation of a native mobile application for iOS/Android using nativescript

Creation of a single web application Back Office System to manage the web application and mobile application.

Creation of backend services using GraphQL to support both application and back office web app,

The scope of the project is to have a internal database of all employees and also tracks labor hours along with geolocation for internal use. *Stack of technologies:* **Nativescript, Angular 4, GraphQL Express Node.js.** 

## **CONSORTIUM LEGAL COSTA RICA**

Internal Cash Flow Management Web Application | 2016 | 5 months

Full migration from a old PC application(Windows Application) to a Single Web Application for one of the more import Law Firms in Costa Rica, the MEAN stack was used to implement the Web Application, specifically MEAN.JS, (Mongo, Express, Angular, Node) I was the Full Stack Developer in charge of the architecture, planning, take of requirements, implementation, DevOps, deployment and continuous integration of the Web Application. It was a financial application to manage the Law Firm's cash flow, including deposits, checks and financial transactions. *Stack of technologies:* MongoDB, Express, AngularJS, Node.

# **4TIUS**

React Native Developer / Fitness Mobile Application | 2016 | 6 months

Worked as Mobile React Developer, responsible of maintenance and optimization for a fitness native mobile application which provides Workout routines to the user based on fitness preferences, this application was built for iOs/Android devices. My tasks included, add new functionality, bug fixing, enhance UI, and apply functional changes. The stack of technologies used for this project was *Stack of technologies*: **React Native+Redux+Apollo GraphQL**.

## STANCE.COM

UI Developer / 2015 (6 months)

UI Developer responsible of functional/UI, creation/maintenance of critical components for a global e-commerce website, in charge of implementation of full landing pages for global campaigns and enhancements of current UI components, optimization of styling using BEM methodology. *Stack of technologies:* **MEAN.io, Node, Magento and Worpress, Grunt, Foundation and Compass** 

# TANSLER.COM

Front End Developer / 2014 (6 months)

UI Developer responsible for creation, development and coordination with the UX/Design Department/Back-End team of new features and maintenance for a Real Estate web application this startup was similar to AirBnb in specs the only difference was that the user could bid for any number of properties and hosts were able to decide if accept the bid or not, because of that, several components were created from scratch. *Stack of technologies*: **AngularJS, RESTful Services, Google Maps Api.**